# Reshav Abraham Full Stack Software Engineer

#### About me

Passionate software engineer with 4 years of experience in Full Stack Development. Experience building backend API's, Front-ends, and deploying Production grade features. Experience with training and serving Machine Learning models. Persistent worker with a positive attitude and always looking for a new challenge.

# Work Experience

#### Narmi

Software Engineer New York, NY

May 2021 - Present

Narmi is a medium sized startup that has been around for 6 years that offers digital account opening and digital banking to mid-tier credit unions and banks.

- · Integrated multiple banking cores which has helped the company grow and expand its customer base.
- · Managed expectations with implementation team to provide clients realistic and accurate timelines.
- Contributed to Narmi's Design System. This is an open source project consisting of front-end design components using React and SASS. https://github.com/narmi/design\_system
- · Integrated with multiple third party APIs for check images and E-Statements. These APIs required knowledge of cryptography and strong networking skills.
- Worked as on On-Call engineer to respond immediately to incidents and monitor spikes in errors on Production Environments

#### **NLmatics**

NLP Engineer New York, NY

July 2019 - April 2021

NLmatics is an early stage startup that specialized in semantic document search. The product was used for analyzing Offering Memorandums for real estate and financial research documents.

- Developed a service to parse and index PDF documents with high fidelity. Implemented and tested document layout analysis algorithms to improve the classification of header, paragraph, and table text. This significantly improved the search quality of the product.
- Lead On-Prem installations for clients and customized deployments for restrictive environments. Prepared installations by simulating client environments. Designed deployment scripts for regular updates and roll-outs.
- Designed Implemented a Search Flagging and Approval System to track regressions and improvements in search quality. This guided the development when testing new changes to the Search Engine pipeline.

### **Dell EMC**

Software Intern Charlotte, NC

May 2017 - August 2017

· Extrapolated memory usage for enterprise data pipelining software by modeling a regression on real-time memory consumption data using Apache Spark.

☑ reshavabraham@gmail.com **८** (908)-731-1426

O reshav-abraham in reshav-abraham ↑ 156 Allen street,

New York, New York, 10002

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages Python, Javascript, Java, Bash

Frameworks React, Django, Pytorch, Tensorflow, React Native

Markup HTML, CSS, Markdown

**DevOps** Docker, Kubernetes, Concourse, GitHub Actions

Cloud GCP, Azure

Databases MongoDB, Postgres

Project Management Zenhub, Jira, Clubhouse Misc Git, Chrome Dev Tools, Web Scraping, Xcode

#### Education

# **B.S.** Computer Engineering

**Purdue University** 

West Lafayette August 2014 - December 2018

#### **Multi-core Processor System Verilog**

• Implemented a synthesizable multi-core processor for processing MIPS assembly language in SystemVerilog.

#### **Automated Nerf-Gun Turret**

- Engineered a turret gun with 3D printed parts, STM32F407VGT7, and Raspberry pi. The turret gun was controllable with a Wii nunchuck and could detect and shoot human targets with a nerf dart.
- · Implemented human-target detection and tracking with MobileNetSSD and OpenCV.

#### **Projects**

#### **Spotify Playlist Maker**

- Implemented a web scraper to scrape Artist data based off of genre on Band Camp.
- · Leveraged Spotify's API to search scraped artists and build playlists.

#### **Voice Detection**

- · Developed a neural network architecture using CNN and linear layers for processing audio signals to identify human voices.
- Developed a script for scraping audio from YouTube
- Utilized MFCC and Signal Processing techniques to prepare data.

# Volunteering

Marcy Lab Volunteer

November 2022 - Present

- Mentored a Marcy Lab student for starting a career in
- · Scheduled in person working sessions to develop the student's skills in software.

# Certificates

# Stanford University, CS224N

- Developed a Neural Machine Language Translation model in PyTorch.
- Implemented Encoder and Decoder networks using LSTM and CNN layers for processing out-of-vocabulary words